Preliminary Inventory of the Committee on the Present Danger records
Hoover Institution Archives
Committee on the Present Danger records
1967-1992
92073
Committee on the Present Danger (U.S.)
494 manuscript boxes (197.6 linear feet)
Hoover Institution Archives Stanford, California 94305-6010
Correspondence, minutes, reports, studies, memoranda, press releases, financial records, clippings, and other printed matter, relating to American politics and foreign policy, Soviet-American relations, and American and Soviet defenses and military policy. Includes some records of the earlier Citizens' Committee for Peace with Freedom in Vietnam, relating to American policy during the Vietnamese War.
Administrative Information
Access
Collection is open for research.
The Hoover Institution Archives only allows access to copies of audiovisual items. To listen to sound recordings or to view videos or films during your visit, please contact the Archives at least two working days before your arrival. We will then advise you of the accessibility of the material you wish to see or hear. Please note that not all audiovisual material is immediately accessible.
Acquisition Information
Acquired by the Hoover Institution Archives in 1992.
Accruals
Materials may have been added to the collection since this finding aid was prepared. To determine if this has occurred, find the collection in Stanford University's online catalog at http://searchworks.stanford.edu/. Materials have been added to the collection if the number of boxes listed in the online catalog is larger than the number of boxes listed in this finding aid.
Biographical/Historical Note
American private organization, founded 1976, promoting a strong national security policy.
Scope and Content of Collection
Correspondence, minutes, reports, studies, memoranda, press releases, financial records, clippings, and other printed matter, relating to American politics and foreign policy, Soviet-American relations, and American and Soviet defenses and military policy. Includes some records of the earlier Citizens' Committee for Peace with Freedom in Vietnam, relating to American policy during the Vietnamese War.
Materials are retained in order as compiled from the boxes. The order in the box has been respected, even when not logical. Similar materials may be found in multiple boxes throughout the collection. Every folder title has been written down in its original spelling, but for few exceptions for typos and capitalization.
Abreviations are used throughout the list, including CPD for Committee on the Present Danger, INF for Intermediate-Range Nuclear Forces Agreement, START for Strategic Arms Reduction Treaty, SALT for Strategic Arms Limitation Talks, and ACDA for the American Conservative Defense Alliance, along with other commonly known governmental abreviations such as CIA and DoD.
Box 89 contains an index, probably compiled in 1990, called "File Cabinets - Master Index." The material it describes has been put, in a somewhat disrupted order, and with many gaps, in the boxes of the present collection.
As a general rule, the boxes listed contain newspaper and journal articles unless when noted otherwise; either in the title of the folders or in the description.
Indexing Terms
The following terms have been used to index the description of this collection in the library's online public access catalog.
Vietnam War, 1961-1975.; United States--Politics and government--1945-1989.; United States--Politics and government--1989-1993.; United States--Foreign relations--1945-1989.; United States--Foreign relations--1989-1993.; United States--Foreign relations--Soviet Union.; Soviet Union--Foreign relations--United States.; United States--Defenses.; United States--Military policy.; Soviet Union--Defenses.; Soviet Union--Military policy.; Citizens' Committee for Peace with Freedom in Vietnam.
Collection Contents
- Citizens Committe for Peace with Freedom in Vietnam (Folder 1)
- Conferences with CPD people (Folder 1)
- 10 audio tapes (cassettes) from August-September 1979 (Folder 1)
- 2 audio tapes (cassettes) from January 1980 ("The 1980 crisis and what we should do about it"). (Folder 1)
- CPD publications, pamphlets, press release, 1977-January 1982. Including "What we have said 1976-1980 and what has been said about us" (Folder 2)
- Material for IRS audit in 1988 (on 1985) by Stephen J. Melnick, IRS (Folder 3)
- IRS Melnick, 1985 (Folder 3)
- CDP profit and loss statement for the year 1985 and payroll, 1985 (Folder 3)
- Annual contributions and saving reports from Riggs, 1976-1988 (Folder 3)
- Contributors, 1989 (Folder 3)
- Contributors in an envelope, 1985 (Folder 3)
- Black ring-binder for IRS audit 1988 (on 1985) (Folder 3)
- Materials from the Department of State on Nicaragua, 1985-1986 (Folder 4)
- Current News, loose issues, 1988-1990 (Folder 4)
- Material for IRS visit on 1985-1988, 1988 (Folder 4)
- Materials on Helionetics, Inc Bankruptcy, 1989 (Folder 5)
- Riggs National Bank, 1985-1991. Includes materials from Roger T. Sanez Public Accountant, 1979-1992, Robert Garfield 1977-1978, CPD cash expenditures and bills to be paid 1976-1986, and Materials on Helionetics, Inc. (of which CPD is a shareholder-200 common shares of Helionetics were donated to CPD by Edward Teller in 1984). (Folder 5)
- Stocks, 1986. Includes Penn Central Corp., Helionetics and Sprague Technologies, Inc. (Folder 5)
- Julia K. Horton, Secretary, 1983-1992 (Folder 6)
- Bob Tarver, Employed, 26 Feb 1990 (Folder 6)
- David J. Trachtenberg, Senior Defense Analyst, 1982-1992 (Folder 6)
- Salary Schedules, payroll, 1980, 1982 (Folder 6)
- Merril Lynch CDs & T-Bills, from 1990 on (Folder 6)
- Merril Lynch miscellaneous (Folder 6)
- Merril Lynch Ready Assets Trust, from 1990 on (Folder 6)
- Loose financial and fiscal material (Employer's Witholding Tax) (Folder 6)
- Federal Form 941, 1986- (Folder 6)
- Federal Form 990, 1986-Comparative statements of receipts and expenditures for the years 1976 (partial) to 1980 (Folder 6)
- Summary of Senate INF Statements (Folder 7)
- Official brochures on Helsinki Commission / CSCE (Folder 7)
- Offical brochures on Technology transfers; allied contributions; NATO (Folder 7)
- 1982-1985 (Folder 7)
- Internal CPD budget and budget projections, 1976-1977 (Folder 7)
- Washington Summit / INF Agreement, 7-10 Dec 1987. Includes Press clippings and official material on INF (Folder 8)
- ANTI-INF (Folder 8)
- INF Amendments (Folder 8)
- INF Questions (Folder 8)
- Daily Summary of Hearings (Folder 8)
- SSCI Report (Folder 8)
- Senate Ratification Debate (Folder 8)
- Prospects for another SALT / START, 1987- 1990 (Folder 9)
- CRS Studies, Clippings and material on SALT, 1981-1984 (Folder 9)
- Status of Negotiations, Charts (Folder 9)
- START Chronology (Folder 9)
- Official and non-official timelines on arms control (START, INF, Strategic Defense Initiative) (Folder 9)
- Negotiators, 1982-1986. Contains articles and a few letters to and from CPD people in the administration (Folder 10)
- Negotiators, 1987-Contains articles and a few letters to and from CPD people in the administration (Folder 10)
- MX (Missile-experimental) articles, 1984 (Folder 11)
- MX articles, 1982-1983 (Folder 12)
- All these folders contain only articles, official and think tank documents and short reports. There are also a few open letters (Folder 13)
- MX Airmoblie (Folder 13)
- MX Carter administration (Folder 13)
- MX Air Force (Folder 13)
- Reagan, Neutron Warhead (Folder 13)
- Neutron Warhead, 1977-1981 (Folder 13)
- MX-1981 (Folder 13)
- MX-1981 (Folder 13)
- All these folders contain only articles, official and think tank documents and short reports. There are also a few open letters (Folder 14)
- MX Decision, 1979 (Folder 14)
- MX ICBM (Missile-experimental Intercontinental Ballistic Missile), 1979 (Folder 14)
- MX Verification (Folder 14)
- MX Dense Pack, Basing Modes (Folder 14)
- MX Criticism and critics (Folder 14)
- MX ICBM, 1980 (Folder 14)
- Nicaragua Loose material, 1984-1985. Including on ICJ case and Soviet activity. Memos from Otto Reich. (Folder 15)
- MX ICBM, 1975, 1977, 1978 (Folder 15)
- TRIDENT, Contains articles and reports on Trident (Folder 15)
- Includes also material on Nicaragua and ICJ case (Folder 15)
- TITAN Missle (Folder 15)
- MX (Folder 15)
- SOP (Standard office procedures) (Folder 16)
- S, Correspondence from Jerry Sanders when he was a PhD student, asking for interviews, and other correspondence (Folder 16)
- Transition, Nov. 1980. Includes correspondence and articles on the transition process and letters from Nitze (Folder 16)
- Sales of books and CPD pamphlets (Folder 16)
- Max Singer, Potomac Organization, Inc. Regarding the creation of a "Citizen's cttee for the pro-democratic coalition in central America" (CCPCCA) (Folder 16)
- Stand Tall America (Folder 16)
- T (Folder 16)
- CPD, Using our titles (Folder 16)
- CPD, Turner, Stansfield CIA (Folder 16)
- Paul Warnke, Contains a speech by Warnke and press clippings (Folder 16)
- Women's Conferences (See also CPD Sulgrave file-File 1) (Folder 16)
- Present Danger and related organizations, contains letters and press clippings on "pro" and "anti" CPD organizations (SANE, American Security Council, CDM) (Folder 17)
- Loose material regarding employment opportunities, resumes... (Folder 17)
- Peddlers of Crisis, contains a few comments on the book and correspondence regarding buying copies (Folder 17)
- Platforms, Democratic and Republican, contains platform texts and a Statement by Nitze and Pipes (text?) before the republican platform cttee (Folder 17)
- Polls (Folder 17)
- Presidential Campaign, 1984 (Folder 17)
- Press mailing list (Folder 17)
- Present Danger, program. Includes "CPD First year program" with budget attached, at least three versions, 11 May 1976, 8 Sept 1976 and 11 Nov 1976 (Folder 17)
- Correspondence with RAND (Folder 17)
- Reader's Digest, on an article by Teller in the RD on Strategic Defense Initiative, 1986 (Folder 17)
- Rowny, Lt. Gen. Edward L. (retired) articles and correspondence, 1980s (Folder 17)
- CPD: Hill Briefings (Folder 18)
- Inquiries-Re: CPD (Folder 18)
- Internships (Folder 18)
- J (Folder 18)
- Kastle Systems, Inc. (Security Cards) (Folder 18)
- Kissinger, Henry. Contains letter from Tyroler to Kissinger 25 July 1979 (Folder 18)
- L, contains two letters from Reagan while president thanking the CPD for its work (Folder 18)
- Letters to the Editor (Folder 18)
- Listing of CPD (Folder 18)
- Lists: Present Danger Prospective Members/ Contributors (Folder 18)
- Kevin Maxwell- Pergamon (Folder 18)
- Present Danger: Media Reaction Reports, contains a report on Media reaction to Initial Press Conf, 11 Nov 1976 (Folder 18)
- M (Folder 18)
- Correspondence and material on the CPD seal (Folder 18)
- New Yorker article, 27 April 1981on the CPD, by R. Barnet and the Boston Globe 28 April 1981 (Folder 18)
- Nuclear Freeze (Folder 18)
- P, contains a memo by Paul Green reporting on the visit of two Russians from TASS (Folder 18)
- Loose material (Folder 19)
- C (Folder 19)
- California Project (Folder 19)
- Cartoons on Carter's foreign policy (Folder 19)
- Center for Foreign Policy Development (Folder 19)
- Proposed China Trip, 1978Contains memo of conversation Nitze and Tyroler with Chinese VP (Folder 19)
- China Papers (Folder 19)
- China Trip (CPD), Nov-77contains notes on the China trip by others (incl. Max Kampelman) (Folder 19)
- China News Clippings (Folder 19)
- The Committee for National Security (Folder 19)
- Congressional Voting (CPD). Contains an issue of Washington Report on National Security Voting Index (scorecard) (Folder 19)
- Cooperating Groups, Present Danger (Folder 19)
- E (Folder 19)
- Foreign Policy Association (Folder 19)
- Foreign Relations, Committe on (Present Danger). Contains a testimony by Nitze 19 Jan 1977 (Folder 19)
- Form Letter Samples, Present Danger (Folder 19)
- GAC Canididates, 1985 (Folder 19)
- Guggenheim, Alan: Foundation for American Communications (Folder 19)
- H, letters from Heritage F (Folder 19)
- Loose material including letters on the transfer of CPD archives to Hoover-contacts begin in 1978 (Folder 19)
- Anti-Groups, Kennan (CPD) (Folder 20)
- Americans for SALT (Folder 20)
- A (Folder 20)
- American Legion Magazine (Folder 20)
- Advertising (Present Danger) (Folder 20)
- Anti Groups, J. Stone (CPD) (Folder 20)
- U.S. Arms Sales (Folder 20)
- Loose material re. the publication of Alerting America (Folder 20)
- Anti (Present Danger) (Folder 20)
- Bibliography (CPD) (Folder 20)
- Bishops, U.S. Council of Catholic (Folder 20)
- Brown, Harold, Secretary of Defense (CPD) (Folder 20)
- The Busby Papers, 11 Sep 1984 (Folder 20)
- Loose material-reviews and catalogues, 1990-1991 (Folder 21)
- B Team. Contains articles and materials on Team B (Folder 21)
- Bibliographies (Folder 21)
- Anti-Submarine Warfare (ASW). Contains materials on U.S. Anti-Submarine Warfare (Folder 22)
- ASW. Letter and memo from Institute fro Defense Analysis (Folder 22)
- Loose material, mainly articles, on Laser ASAT (Anti-Satellite Weapon) (Folder 22)
- Lasers (Folder 22)
- ASAT (Folder 22)
- Loose material, articles mainly on NASA (Folder 23)
- Loose material, articles mainly on NASA (Folder 24)
- Science Advisor (Folder 24)
- Nuclear Power (Folder 24)
- U.S. Strategic Materials. Contains articles, reports on strategic minerals (Folder 24)
- Loose issues of Current News (Folder 24)
- Nuclear Stockpile Materials (Folder 25)
- Loose issues of Current News (Folder 25)
- Loose issues of Current News (Folder 26)
- Loose articles on Iran-Contra affair (Folder 26)
- Loose articles on Iran-Contra affair (Folder 27)
- Maps (Folder 27)
- Nuclear Freeze Issue (Folder 28)
- Freeze Conference, 1982. Contains material on the conference of Oct 19, 1982, sponsored by the Washington Jounalism Center, featuring Iklé, Warnke, Barnet, Molander, Barlow, Hehir, McCornack, Ronald Lehman, Joseph Lehman, Waller, Berezhkov, Buerstedde, Zumwalt (Folder 28)
- SALT II, U.S. Senate Armed Services Committee, 2 August 1979, PM: Kissinger. Contains material on Catholic Bishops Appeal to Nuclear Freeze (Folder 28)
- Nuclear Freeze, 1984 (Folder 29)
- NATO: Protests (Folder 29)
- articles on the Nuclear Freeze Movement (Folder 29)
- Nuclear Freeze, 1983 (Folder 30)
- Loose issues of Current News (Folder 30)
- Loose issues of Current News (Folder 31)
- Carter Administration-Selected Statements, 1978 (Folder 32)
- Carter Administration- Selected Statements, 1979 (Folder 32)
- Issues of Current News (Folder 32)
- Articles on chemical weapons (Folder 33)
- Articles on chemical weapons (Folder 34)
- American Conservative Defense Alliance (ACDA) Analysis of Civil Defense. Contains a study by ACDA on Civil Defense and an Evaluation of the paper and the issue by CPD in late 1978-early 1979 (Folder 35)
- ACDA, "An Analysis of Civil Defense in Nuclear War" (Folder 35)
- Soviet Civil Defense. Contains articles, official reports and other materials, including in russian, on civil defense (Folder 35)
- Civil Defense. Contains material on U.S. civil defense (Folder 35)
- CIA, "Soviet Civil Defense" Contains a report by the CIA on Soviet civil Defense (Folder 35)
- Command Control Communications articles (Folder 36)
- U.S. Security Assistance (Folder 37)
- Conventional arms sales and transfers articles and reports (Folder 37)
- Comprehensive Test Ban Treaty articles and reports (Folder 37)
- Citizens Committe for Peace with Freedom in Vietnam materials (Folder 38-42)
- 1988 Candidates' Statements (Folder 43)
- Pre-1988 Campaign (Folder 43)
- 1988 Platforms (Folder 43)
- Candidates (Folder 43)
- Party Platforms, 1984 (Folder 43)
- Bentsen, 12 July 1988 (Folder 44)
- California, New Jersey Primaries, 7 June 1988 (Folder 44)
- New York Primary, 19 Apr 1988 (Folder 44)
- Other state primaries, 1988 (Folder 44)
- Articles on the 1988 presidential elections, as well as on the conventions for Bush and Dukakis campaigns (Folder 45-46)
- Pergamon Project. Contains materials on the publication of Alerting America, including a letter by John Poindexter authorizing the publication of Reagan's letters to CPD (Folder 47)
- Loose issue of Surviving Together-An Update on Soviet-American Relations, 1984-1986 (Folder 47)
- Is America Catching Up? (Folder 48)
- Reaction to Catch Up (Folder 48)
- Reaction to CPD polls (Folder 48)
- Reaction to CPD brochure, U.S. Public Attitudes Toward: a) The Nuclear Freeze and Other Nuclear Arms Issues; b) the U.S. Defense Effort. (Folder 48)
- Loose material, mainly articles, on Alerting America and Pergamon, including an assesments of sales (Folder 48)
- Galleys for Alerting America (Folder 48)
- Defense and the deficit 8 March 1985. Contains material, including press release, on the brochure Defense and the Deficit produced by CPD. (Folder 49)
- Also contains transcripts of the hearings on the Iran-contra affair (Folder 49)
- Transcripts of the hearings on the Iran-contra affair (Folder 50-53)
- ACDA press clippings (Folder 54)
- Loose articles on defense-related issues after the Cold War, particularly JCS (Folder 54)
- Attorney General (Folder 54)
- Incoming Bush administration departments and agencies materials, including John Tower's failed confirmation by the Senate. (Folder 54)
- Loose material (Folder 55)
- Testimony of Prof. Richard Pipes, Harvard University, before the Senate Armed Services Committee, 16 October 1979 (Folder 55)
- Testimony of the Honorable Fred C. Iklé, former director of the U.S. Arms Control and Disarmament Agency before the Cttee on Armed Services, U.S. Senate, 10 October 1979 (Folder 55)
- Statement of Dr. Edward Teller before the Senate Cttee on Foreign Relations, 7 September 1979 (Folder 55)
- Statement of Donald G. Brennan on SALT II before the U.S. Senate scheduled for 10 September 1979 (Folder 55)
- Issues of varied magazines and reports (Trilateral Journal, Clarion Call...) (Folder 55)
- Loose material (Folder 56)
- Varied booklets and magazines (Folder 56)
- Issues of Presidential Campaign Hotline, 1988 (Folder 56)
- Loose articles on the Gulf Crisis, August 1990 (Folder 57-58)
- Middle East 1989-July 1990 (Folder 59)
- Middle East 1987-1988 (Folder 59)
- Middle East articles, 1985-1986. Includes Libya (Folder 60)
- Middle East articles, 1984Includes Lebanon bombing (Folder 60)
- Middle East, November 1990 (Folder 61)
- Loose issues of military magazines (Folder 61)
- Loose materials (Folder 62)
- U.S. Arms Control Objectives and the Implications for Ballistic Missile DefenseTranscript of a Harvard University Symposium, 1-2 November 1979 (Folder 62)
- Issues of military and other magazines (Folder 62)
- Soviet Military Thought on Global Nuclear War manuscript,by J.D. Douglass, Jr. and A.M. Hoeber, Oct 1978 (Folder 62)
- Memo on Nuclear Force Programs & Costs, Counter-DOD-FY81 Proposal, Bill Van Cleave and Bill Graham (Folder 62)
- Statement of professor William R. Van Cleave on U.S. Strategic Force Programs and Options before the House Armed Services Committee, 14 March 1980 (Folder 62)
- Foreign Policy and Foreign Affairs, two articles by Nitze (Folder 62)
- ACDA. contains draft and final version of a Press Release, "Research and Analysis Memorandum issued by the Executive Committee of the Committee on the Present Danger," 9/29/1978: An Evaluation of "U.S. and Soviet strategic Capability through the mid-1980s (Folder 63)
- ACDA offical materials and press clippings (Folder 63)
- Loose material on ACDA, 1984-1986. Contains also speeches and remarks by Eugene Rostow, Memo ACDA Fact Sheets, and articles on ACDA, 1984-1987 (Folder 63)
- Press clippings on ACDA, 1982-1983. Includes Rostow's dismissal on 12 January 1983 (Folder 64)
- Press clippings on CIA, 1981-1992 (Folder 65)
- Military magazines (Folder 65)
- Iran-Contra affair, chronology of press coverage (Folder 66)
- General Advisory Committee, Contains materials on the General Advisory Committee on Arms Control and Disarmament (GAC) (Folder 66)
- Post series on DNA (Folder 66)
- Loose material on ACDA, 1980-1988, including many speeches by Rostow (Folder 66)
- Loose material on NSC, 1981-1989 (Folder 67)
- INF statements and testimonies, early 1988. Includes Kampelman, Weinberger, McNamara, Harold Brown, Nitze, David Abshire, William P. Rogers, Bill Van Cleave, James Schlesinger, Ray Garthoff, Slocombe, Rowny, Perle, Warnke, Gaffney, Teller, and Rostow. (Folder 68)
- INF Hearings (continued) (Folder 69-70)
- SALT Briefing Book: A Commentary on Official Claims, produced by CPD, circa end of 1978, followed by Why We Oppose SALT II (Folder 71)
- Ken Adleman confirmation hearings (Folder 71)
- SALT II Agreement, Vienna, 18 June 1979. Official Document with papers and notes inserted (Folder 71)
- INF Treaty text, December 1987 (Folder 71)
- Amendments proposed during Senate Floor Debate, May 1988 (Folder 71)
- INF Treaty Hearings Daily Summaries (Folder 71)
- DoD Telephone Directory (Folder 72)
- SALT publications, articles and brochures, including The SALT Handbook, edited by Michael B. Donley, produced by The Heritage Foundation; articles by David Yost, Will Van Cleave and others. (Folder 72)
- Strategic Studies Center-SRI International brochures "Executive Summary" on Telecommunications (Folder 72)
- DoD Annual Report, Fiscal Year 1982 (Folder 72)
- Modified Defense Program, study results, undertaken under the direction of W. Van Cleave on a tentative defense program for Ronald Reagan, March 1980-March 1981. Includes recommendations on Strategic Nuclear Forces, General Purpose Forces, etc. with corre (Folder 73)
- Printed Memo with press clippings by Jesse Helms on INF Treaty. (Folder 73)
- Readiness (Folder 74)
- Military Reform Caucus (Folder 74)
- Defense: Is the U.S. Prepared? New York Times, 21 September 1980 to 27 September 1980 (Folder 75)
- U.S. Defense Manpower (Folder 75)
- U.S. Defense Manpower (Folder 76)
- Grand Strategy Legislative file. Contains a project proposal by CPD for the Trustees of the Smith Richardson Foundation, "A Grand Strategy for the Free World" (Folder 76)
- Nuclear Strategy: PD-59. Contains articles, papers, reaction to Carter's new nuclear strategy (Folder 77)
- Loose material on U.S. Strategy (Folder 77)
- U.S. Strategy (Folder 77)
- Current News, 1981-1983 (Folder 78)
- Current News, 1982-1983 (Folder 79)
- U.S.-Soviet Theater Nuclear Balance (Folder 80)
- U.S. Tactical Missiles (Folder 80)
- S.T. Cohen, contains drafts and articles by Sam Cohen, the inventor of the neutron bomb (Folder 80)
- Van Cleave, William and Gray. Contains materials, including articles, testimonies on SALT, ICBM vulnerability, NATO nuclear deterrence; speeches, notes, and memos, including a "Memo To SALT Group on Cruise Missles," 15 July 1979; letters, including a lett (Folder 80)
- Correspondence with WRV and Science (Folder 80)
- Zumwalt, Elmo, letters, articles and op-eds, memos, speeches, 1979-1989 (Folder 80)
- Yugoslavia (Folder 81)
- XM-1 (Army Tank Program) (Folder 81)
- Representative Charles Wilson (Folder 81)
- Propaganda (Folder 81)
- Proliferation (Folder 82)
- Current News, 1985-1986 (Folder 82)
- Current News, 1985-1987 (Folder 83)
- Current News on Terrorism (Folder 84)
- Transcripts of the hearings on the Iran-contra affair (Folder 84)
- Transcripts of the hearings on the Iran-contra affair (Folder 85)
- Soviet Production (Folder 85)
- Kupperman, Charles Martin (Folder 86)
- SALT II Agreement and related material, Vienna, 18 June 1979 (Folder 86)
- The Failure of SALT II in National Defense by Kupperman (Folder 86)
- The Price of Defense review by Charles Kupperman, Boston Study Group, 25 April 1979 (Folder 86)
- Kupperman, Charles Martin. Contains numerous analysis, including an Analysis of President Carter's SALT Speech, 25 April 1979; The Price of SALT II; The Soviet World View (Folder 86)